Guide to the KUED-TV Utah World War II Stories audio visual collection 2004-2006
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
KUED-TV Utah World War II Stories audio visual collection
2004-2006
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 801-581-8864 http://www.lib.utah.edu/collections/multimedia-archives/
A1171
KUED-TV (Television station: Salt Lake City, Utah)
83 DVDs
This collection contains oral history interviews with 80 Utahns about their lives during World War II, at home and abroad.
Historical Note
The men and women of the "The Greatest Generation" recollect the pivotal events of World War II in the landmark, Emmy Award-winning, four-part series from KUED. This collection is comprised of the oral histories that informed this series. Utah sent more than 70,000 troops to war – to the jungles of Asia, the mountains of Italy, the beaches of France, the air over Berlin, and the waters of the Pacific – to battle the forces of tyranny and reclaim freedom. More than 3,600 never returned to tell their stories. Those who did carry with them an unwavering sense of pride and unfailing humility about their service. At home, Utah citizens worked and sacrifices to help support the war effort, while anxiously waiting for the return of soldiers from distant combat.
Recordings of all interviews are available on DVD for research purposes only.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
Donated by in.
See also the KUED-TV productions audio-visual collection and the KUED-TV promotional materials (Acc 409) and records Acc 176, Acc 355, and Acc 374 in the University Archives Records Management Division of Special Collections.
Public television--Utah--History--Sources; Educational television stations--Utah--History--Sources; Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences; Journalism; Material Types; Oral Histories; Moving Images; Sound Recordings; Sound Recordings; Moving Images
- LaVell Bigelow, United States Navy Captain, April 20, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 1)
- Orson Blackett, United States Navy Lieutenant, May 23, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 2)
- Don Verle Breinholt, United States Army Staff Sergeant, April 25, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 3)
- Gladys Breinholt, civilian, April 25, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 4)
- Clint Brewer, United States Army T5 Sergeant, April 14, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 5)
- Art Buell, United States Navy Machinist Mate 1st Class, May 9, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 6)
- Richard Burt, United States Army Air Corps Staff Sergeant, August 10, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 7)
- Don Buswell, United States Navy Lieutenant Commander, April 22, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 8)
- LauRene Buswell, civilian, April 22, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 9)
- Heber Butler, United States Army Air Corps Flight Officer, November 28, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 10)
- William Christensen, United States Army Sergeant, February 15, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 11)
- Emmett S. Davis, United States Army Air Corps Colonel, February 1, 2006; DVD Color, sound (Disc 12)
- Norma Day, United States Navy Communications Specialist, April 14, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 13)
- Maurine Draper, civilian, Manti Parachute Plant, April 13, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 14)
- MJ Eschler, United States Army Tank Commander, November 16, 2004; DVD Color, sound (Disc 15)
- Spencer Felt, United States Army Air Corps 2nd Lieutenant, May 24, 2004; DVD Color, sound (Disc 16)
- Byrne Fernelius, United States Navy Captain, May 23, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 17)
- Jean Fernelius, civilian, May 23, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 18)
- Max Gollaher, United States Navy Quartermaster, May 24, 2004; DVD Color, sound (Disc 19)
- Epafanio Gonzales, United States Army Combat Engineer, October 24, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 20)
- Calvin Gould, United States Navy Quartermaster, April 13, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 21)
- Joan Gould, United States Navy Lieutenant, April 13, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 22)
- Mary Gray, United States Army 2nd Lieutenant, April 29, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 23)
- Gayle Greetham, civilian, Topaz Internment Camp, July 27, 2006; DVD Color, sound (Disc 24)
- Thomas Harrison, United States Army 1st Lieutenant, February 13, 2004; DVD Color, sound (Disc 25)
- Lillian Heenan, United States Army Nurse Corps 1st Lieutenant, November 17, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 26)
- Douglas Howard, United States Army Sergeant, November 15, 2004 and August 10, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 27)
- Dean Hurst, civilian, April 22, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 28)
- Edmond Press Howard, United States Army 2nd Lieutenant, February 13, 2004; DVD Color, sound (Disc 29)
- Ora Mae Hyatt, United States Army 2nd Lieutenant, February 13, 2004; DVD Color, sound (Disc 30)
- Allan C. Jackson, United States Army Sergeant, May 10, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 31)
- Gene Jacobsen, United States Army Air Corps Supply Sergeant, November 23, 2004; DVD Color, sound (Disc 32)
- Woody James, United States Navy Coxswain, November 15, 2004; DVD Color, sound (Disc 33)
- Bill Johnson, United States Army Staff Sergeant, November 16, 2004; DVD Color, sound (Disc 34)
- Crit W. Killen, United States Navy Chief Gunner's Mate, October 24, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 35)
- Glen Lewis Jr., United States Army Air Corps 2nd Lieutenant, December 16, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 36)
- Leslie G. Lund, United States Army Air Corps Sergeant, July 9, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 37)
- Gayle Macey, civilian, July 27, 2006; DVD Color, sound (Disc 38)
- Ray T. Matheny, United States Army Air Corps Tech Sergeant (disc 1 of 2), February 24, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 39)
- Ray T. Matheny, United States Army Air Corps Tech Sergeant (disc 2 of 2), April 14, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 40)
- Shig Matsukowa, United States Army Private First Class and Raymond Uno, Unites States Military Intelligence Service Corporal, February 13, 2004; DVD Color, sound (Disc 41)
- Brit McConkie, United States Army Tank Commander, November 17, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 42)
- Bob McGregor-Unites States Army Air Corps 2nd Lieutenant, May 10, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 43)
- Gilbert McLean, United States Army Corporal, February 14, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 44)
- Cal McPhie, United States Navy Petty Officer, February 13, 2004; DVD Color, sound (Disc 45)
- Ernie Mettenet, United States Army 1st Sergeant, February 13, 2004 and August 10, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 46)
- Mont Mickelson, United States Army Air Corps Machinist, May 10, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 47)
- Frank Mjaatvedt, United States Army Private First Class, September 28, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 48)
- Ted Nagata, internee, Topaz Internment Camp, July 27, 2006; DVD Color, sound (Disc 49)
- Chase Nielsen, United States Army Air Corps Lieutenant Colonel, February 22, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 50)
- Eugene Nielsen, United States Army Private First Class, January 24, 2006 and April 20, 2006; DVD Color, sound (Disc 51)
- Glenn Parkin, United States Navy Seaman (disc 1 of 2), January 24, 2006; DVD Color, sound (Disc 52)
- Glenn Parkin, United States Navy Seaman (disc 2 of 2), January 24, 2006; DVD Color, sound (Disc 53)
- Gale "Pat" Patterson, United States Army Air Corps 2nd Lieutenant, April 25, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 54)
- Elwin Petersen, United States Navy Lieutenant Commander, February 1, 2006; DVD Color, sound (Disc 55)
- Ken Potts, United States Navy Coxswain, February 24, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 56)
- Steve Poulos, United States Army Sergeant, October 19, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 57)
- Jim Powell, United States Army Sergeant, February 15, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 58)
- Howard Randle, civilian, April 13, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 59)
- Keith Renstrom, United States Marine Corps Gunnery Sergeant (disc 1 of 2), December 16, 2005 and January 24, 2006; DVD Color, sound (Disc 60)
- Keith Renstrom, United States Marine Corps Gunnery Sergeant (disc 2 of 2), December 16, 2005 and January 24, 2006; DVD Color, sound (Disc 61)
- Bill Rice, United States Navy Lieutenant, October 24, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 62)
- Lorraine Robinson, United States Marine Corps Aviation Machinist's Mate, August 10, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 63)
- Jack Russell, United States Marine Corps Private First Class, April 22, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 64)
- Robert Shaffer, United States Marine Corps Captain, April 25, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 65)
- Bill Shanley, United States Army Private First Class, April 24, 2004; DVD Color, sound (Disc 66)
- Joel Shapiro, United States Army, Intelligence Section, XV Corps, May 9, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 67)
- Phil Shumway, United States Navy 1st Lieutenant, February 24, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 68)
- Louis Slama, United States Army Sergeant (2 discs), November 16, 2004 and August 10, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 70)
- Walter Stewart, United States Army Air Corps Colonel, April 29, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 71)
- Barbara Tanner, civilian, May 9, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 72)
- Norman Tanner, United States Army Artillery Pilot, May 9, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 73)
- William Taylor, United States Navy Petty Officer, February 14, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 74)
- Jim Tazoi, United States Army Private First Class, February 14, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 75)
- Kimiko Tazoi, civilian, February 22, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 76)
- Roy Tew, United States Army Air Corps 1st Lieutenant, April 20, 2006; DVD Color, sound (Disc 77)
- Lee Tucker, United States Army Air Corps Captain, May 9, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 78)
- Verna Van Etten, civilian, April 25, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 79)
- George Wahlen, United States Navy Mate 2nd Class, May 24, 2004; DVD Color, sound (Disc 80)
- William Wassmer, United States Navy Fireman 1st Class, April 25, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 81)
- Ruby Whitehead, civilian, May 10, 2005; DVD Color, sound (Disc 82)
- Carl Workman, United States Army Seargent, February 14, 2006; DVD Color, sound (Disc 83)